pythonspot.com 2019-10-29

# Privacy Policy - Python Tutorial

## Who we are

Our website address is: [https://pythonspot.com](https://pythonspot.com/).

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We automatically collects certain information using third-party analytics and / or log programs to help us understand how our users use the Website, but none of this information identifies you personally. All of this information is anonymized. We use this information only to better understand your needs and the needs of Website users in the aggregate, and to be able to trace fraudulent activities if necessary. We also makes use of information gathered for statistical purposes to keep track of the number of visits to the Website and which pages on the Website with a view to introducing improvements.

We share your data with: Our processing partners:

  * CloudFlare, Inc
  * Proinity LLC
  * Vultr Holdings Corporation

Our business partners:

  * Rakuten, Inc
  * Google, Inc
  * Amazon, LCC

Connected third parties:

  * Google, Inc
  * Twitter, Inc
  * Facebook, Inc

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Additional information

### How we protect your data

We do our best to keep your Personal Data safe. We use safe protocols for communication and transferring data (such as HTTPS). We use anonymising and pseudonymising where suitable. We monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks. Even though we try our best we can not guarantee the security of information. However, we promise to notify suitable authorities of data breaches. We will also notify you if there is a threat to your rights or interests. We will do everything we reasonably can to prevent security breaches and to assist authorities should any breaches occur.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

In the event of a data breach we will act quickly to identify what data has been compromised and notify anyone affected. We do not keep any sensitive billing, financial or sales data on our website so any impact would be minimal.

### What third parties we receive data from

We may receive data from our trusted third parties, processing or business parties.

### What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data

None, except for legal or security reasons.

## Cookies and Third-Party Advertisements

The Website uses Google, a third party vendor, to serve advertisements on the Website. In order to serve these advertisements, Google makes use of cookies, including the DART cookie, which enables it to serve ads to Website users based on their visit to the Website and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

## Limitation of Liability

We will not be held liable for any damages resulting from the misuse of any information collected through the Website by any third party, or any misuse of any information collected through the Website not in violation of the Policy.

## Amazon Associates Program

This web­site is a par­tic­i­pant in the Ama­zon Ser­vices LLC As­so­ci­ates Pro­gram. This means, in par­tic­u­lar, that if you fol­low a link to amazon.​com or any other na­tional ver­sion of Ama­zon web­site and then make a pur­chase within 24 hours, I will re­ceive a small per­cent­age of what you pay to Ama­zon (but your price will stay ex­actly the same). I, how­ever, never link to spe­cific prod­ucts just in or­der to ad­ver­tize them. I link only to the prod­ucts that I gen­uinely find help­ful and the web­pages link­ing to such prod­ucts ex­press my hon­est opin­ion on the prod­ucts. In other words, I never rec­om­mend a prod­uct just in or­der to per­suade you to buy it; I rec­om­mend it be­cause I my­self find it use­ful.
